Hello, everyone. So in this video, I'll be doing just an example of mathematical induction trees.
So recall, so let's firstly recall the following. Recall the following three functions, right?
So the function list set, which takes a list and gives you a set and that was defined recursively
as follows. So list set takes an empty list and returns the empty set. And list set for the second
equation takes an empty list and returns to you the set that has x and list set x's. And recall also
another function that does the same thing for trees. So tree set, right? Where tree set of a leaf
is the empty list and tree of an empty tree. So Node, L, A, R equals insert A in tree set, L union set.
Okay, let's call that, clarify the handwriting a bit. Lastly, recall the in-order traversal function
for trees. So it's called in-order and it takes a tree and returns a list. In-order was for an
empty tree gives you an empty list. And for a non-empty tree, it gives you that list. So in-order
traversal of the left subtree and then the root and the in-order traversal of the right.
So this is, remember these functions. Now we want to prove the following. We want to show that
list set of the in-order traversal of a given tree for any tree is the same as the tree
set of tree. So we basically want to show that in-order traversal doesn't lose any tree elements.